Product Designer & Strategy

EXPERIENCE

Product Designer at QuillBot

JULY 2023 - PRESENT

- 1. Led **design research**, such as quantitative data, competitive & market analysis, user feedback, site metrics, and usability testing.
- 2. Collaborate with **cross-functional teams** on a daily basis to achieve business and user goals that include product managers, engineers, and designers.
- 3. Currently leading Cross-pollination team to achieve OKR impact of business **Grow browser extensions** and get product market fit on apps.
- 4. Redesign the Paraphrasing-Tool.com domain website, which resulted in a **75**% clicks improvement on a daily level basis, ranking from *10th to 6th* position in the
- 5. Achieved a **125% improvement** in CTR and a **131% increase in extension installs** through comprehensive user research and iterative prototyping.
- 6. Led a comprehensive UI refresh of QuillBot's homepage with a focus on enhancing brand presence, resulting in a **600% increase** in clicks compared to the baseline, as validated through A/B testing.
- Collaborated with internal stakeholders to deeply understand product goals and user needs.
- 8. Optimised Top header for promoting chrome extension, resulting in a **20% increase** in click and improvement in retention.

Product Designer at Squareboat

JAN 2022 - JULY 2023

- 1. Responsible for leading multiple projects for startups and enterprise clients. Successfully **delivered 16+ digital experiences** for clients like Dr. Reddy's, SISO, Huddle, Accacia and more.
- 2. **Mentored a team of designers**, providing guidance and support on various project.
- 3. Create a wide range of **design system for Fastn using tokens** which helps in building your next web project faster with fastn
- 4. Worked closely as **Founder Member at Grid Design Studio** by conducting design reviews, ensuring the product is accessible, inclusive, and aligned with user needs.
- 5. Collaborated closely with **developers** to ensure accurate implementation of designs.

Junior UI/UX Designer at ECHO India

JUN 2020 - JAN 2022

- 1. Worked on **redesigning** the company's website.
- 2. Leading designing the **master design system** to maintain consistency in the product.
- 3. Collaborated with internal stakeholders to deeply understand **product goals and user needs.**
- 4. Developed comprehensive **UX flows** to ensure a smooth, streamlined, intuitive experience for users across platform.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Product-cum-Growth Designer with 4+ years of industry experience who believes in creating engaging design experience in the digital world. My strength lies in defining the product vision, crafting compelling user stories and designing seamless human-centered experiences across complex ecosystems.

SKILLS

Design Skills: UX/UI Design, Wireframing,
Prototyping, User Research, Usability Testing,
Journey Mapping, Storytelling, Product Design
Technical Skills/Tools: Figma, AdobeXD, Miro,
Google Analytics, Amplitude, Jira, Notion, Microsoft
Clarity, Usability Testing

Collaboration & Project Management: Cross-Functional Collaboration, Agile Methodologies, Task Prioritization, Stakeholder Communication Key Strengths: Design Systems, Interaction Design, Conversion Optimization, A/B Testing, User Personas, Information Architecture, Rapid Experimentation

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology(B.Tech)

Specialisation in Computer science

ECHELON INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY - (2016 - 2020)

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1. Top Performer APRIL 2022
- 2. Designathon Winner August 2023

LINKS

Portfolio - https://www.muskaanverma.in/

Behance - www.behance.net/muskanverma1